Guide to the Erich Maria Remarque Papers MSS.095
Fales Library and Special Collections
- 2003 Accretion, 28.5 Linear Feet in 44 manuscript boxes, 4 oversized flat boxes, 3 box binders, 3 card boxes, 2 oversized folders, and 1 film can.
  - Series III: Art, textile and jewelry collections
    - Subseries B: Catalogs
      - Antiquities and Tribal Art also Islamic, Indian, Nepalese, Tibetan and South-East Asian Art, February 27, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - Chinese Jades and Decorative Arts, March 7, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - Chinese Porcelain and Works of Art, March 21, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Medieval, Renaissance and Baroque Works of Art, April 13, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Oriental Ceramics and Works of Art, April 18, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Works of Art English Furniture and Continental, October 13, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - American and European Decorative Works of Art, Paintings, Furniture and Rugs, April 22-26, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - American and European Paintings, Watercolors, Drawings and Sculpture Sale 621, May 2-3, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - American and European Decorative Works of Art, Paintings, Furniture and Rugs Sale 624, May 6-10, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Decorations, Paintings, Furniture, Rugs, African, Oceanic and Pre-Columbian Works of Art Lot 259, September 30-October 4, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Fine Rugs and Carpets, October 7-12, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Toys, Dolls, Miniatures, Original Comic Strip Art and Disney Celluloids, December 6, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Decorative Works of Art, Paintings and Furniture, April 7-11, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Impressionist and Modern Paintings and Sculpture, November 7, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - The Paulette Goddard Remarque Collection of Impressionist Paintings Pastels and Drawings, November 7, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - Important 19th and 20th Century Drawings and Watercolors, November 8, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - Nineteenth and Twentieth Century Mexican Paintings, Drawings, Sculptures and Prints, May 9, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - Oriental Ceramics and Works of Art, October 14, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - Oriental Ceramics and Works of Art, December 2, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - Fine Chinese and Korean Ceramics and Works of Art, December 16-17, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - Important Latin American Paintings, Drawings and Sculpture, May 29-30, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - Decorative Works of Art, Furniture, Oriental Rugs and Carpets and Paintings, July 16-17, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Decorative Works of Art, Furniture and Oriental Rugs and Carpets, September 10, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Decorative Works of Art, Collectibles, Furniture, Oriental Rugs and Carpets and Paintings, September 17-18, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - French and Continental Furniture, Decorations and Carpets, October 5, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Antiquities and Islamic Works of Art, November 21-22, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Pre-Columbian Art, November 26, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Fine Chinese Ceramics and Works of Art, December 4, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Old Master, Modern and Contemporary Prints, March 6-7, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Important 19th Century European Paintings, Drawings and Watercolors, May 22, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Fine Oriental and European Carpets, May 31, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Antiquities and Islamic Works of Art, May 30, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Impressionist, Modern and Contemporary Paintings, Drawings and Sculpture, October 8, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Fine Oriental and European Carpets, December 13, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 13)
      - Important 19th Century European Paintings, Drawings and Watercolors, May 21, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Impressionist and Modern Paintings, Drawings and Sculpture, October 7, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Impressionist and Modern Paintings, Drawings and Sculpture, October 6, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Pre-Columbian, Tribal, Antiquities, Decorations, Furniture, and Oriental Rugs and Carpets, December 12, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Silver, Decorations, Furniture and Oriental Rugs and Carpets, December 19, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Contemporary Art, Part III, November 9-10, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Latin American Art, November 20-21, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - French and Continental Furniture, and Decorations, September 30, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Contemporary Prints, February 16-17, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Magnificent jewelry, April 23-24, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - French and Continental Furniture and Decorations, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Coins, Medals and Paper Money, October 5, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Modern and Contemporary Paintings, Drawings and Sculpture, October 10, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Magnificent Jewelry, October 24-25, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Fine Chinese Ceramics and Works of Art, November 7, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Antiquities and Islamic Art, November 28, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Fine Oriental and European Carpets, December 8, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Decorations Including Antiquities and Pre-Columbian Art, Furniture, Rugs and Carpets, December 19, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Old Master Drawings, January 8, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Decorations, Furniture, Rugs and Carpets, March 5, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Decorations, Furniture, Rugs and Carpets, March 26, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - European Works of Arts, Arms and Armour, Furniture and Tapestries, January 12-15, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Old Master Paintings and Drawings, January 17, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Decorations, Furniture, Rugs and Carpets, January 23, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Silver, Decorations, Furniture, Rugs and Carpets, February 20, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - 19th and 20th Century and Contemporary Prints, February 21-22, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Fine Oriental and European Carpets, April 10, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - French and Continental Furniture and Decorations, April 13, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - Antiquities, Indian and Pre-Columbian Art, June 19, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Decorations, Furniture, Rugs and Carpets, July 16, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - Decorations, Furniture, Rugs and Carpets, August 13, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 10)
      - Fine Chinese Ceramics and Works of Art, December 1-2, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - Christie's Fine Chinese Ceramics and Works of Art, December 3, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - German Porcelain Catalogs, undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Series IV: Short story manuscripts
    Series IV: Short story manuscripts consists of mostly typed manuscripts, many with handwritten notes. It is arranged alphabetically by story title.
    Manuscripts are in German
    - Der Abschied, undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Ein Auswanderer, undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Billy, undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Der Chauffeur in Himmel, undated (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Cosi fan Tutte!, undated (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Decadence, undated (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Froschkonzert, undated (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Gesprach auf Deck, undated (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Der Grosse Zauber, undated (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Hymne auf den Cocktail, undated (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - "Ich hab die Nacht Getraumet - - -", undated (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Inshalla, undated (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - Kai, undated (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - Karl Broeger in Fleury, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Kunstausstallung in der Kestnargesellschaft, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Meine Chaiselongue, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Mixen, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Mossik der Geschehnisse, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Natur und Kunstwerk, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Novembernebel, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Phantastische Nacht, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Reisen im Kraftwagen, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Reiza nach Baalbek (?), undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Des Rennen Vanderveldes, undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Ritter vom Knatternden Motor, undated (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Schweigen um Verdun, undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - See in der Nacht, undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Silhouette von Jang-Tse-Kiang (3), undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Sonderbare Schicksale Josek Thiedemann, undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Spuk in der Schniedestrasse, undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Steppengewitter, undated (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Strassenbilder einst und jetzt, undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Stunde, undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Der Tamilenboy, undated (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Die Technik des erfolgreichen Inserats, undated (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Der Teppichweber von Beirut, undated (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Die Toetliche Freiheit zum Tode Karl Haus, undated (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Ein Trauriger Ort, undated (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Treues Fahrrad, es ist Fruhling!, undated (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - En Twicklungsmoglichkelten, undated (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Umrankter Giebel, undated (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - Unterwegs, undated (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Volken, undated (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Wenn man das Auto au Hause Lasst, undated (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - Wie Tanzt Man Diesel Winter?, undated (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - Wiles Erfindung, undated (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - Zwei Tote, undated (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - Misc. Articles, undated (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - Untitled Articles/Stories, undated (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Series V: Paulette Goddard personal materials
    Series V: Paulette Goddard personal materials consists of correspondence, engagement books and planners. The bulk of the correspondence is from Paulette Goddard to her mother, Alta Goddard, although it includes letters from Erich Maria Remarque and several other correspondents to Paulette Goddard.
    - Cards to Paulette Goddard [from Erich Maria Remarque?], circa 1958 (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - Paulette Goddard to Alta Goddard, 1962-1964 (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence - Paulette Goddard to Alta Goddard (Mother), 1965-1966 (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - Erich Maria Remarque to Paulette Goddard, 1959-1966 (Box 41, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence - Paulette Goddard to Alta Goddard (Mother), 1967 (Box 41, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence - Paulette Goddard to Alta Goddard (Mother), 1968 (Box 41, Folder 42)
    - Paulette Goddard to Alta Goddard (Mother), 1969 (Box 41, Folder 43)
    - Erich Maria Remarque to Alta Goddard, 1962-1970 (Box 41, Folder 44)
    - Paulette Goddard - Marriage Certificate, Copies of Marriage, Birth Certificates, undated, 1958, circa 1972 (Box 41, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence - Paulette Goddard to Alta Goddard (Mother), 1970-1973 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Letters and Cards to Paulette Goddard, 1945-1972 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Newsclippings: Photocopies of Articles, 1961-1977 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Paulette Goddard to Alta Goddard (Mother), 1974-1980 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - PG - Engagement Book, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - PG - Engagement Book, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - PG - Planner, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - PG - Engagement Book, 1989-1990 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - PG to Alta Goddard (Mother) 1 of 4, undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - PG to Alta Goddard (Mother) 2 of 4, undated (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - PG to Alta Goddard (Mother) 3 of 4, undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - PG to Alta Goddard (Mother) 4 of 4, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Paulette Goddard Personal - Screenplay - L'Americana, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Redgrave, Michael. The Film "Antony and Cleopatra", undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Address Book, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Address Book, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Address Book, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Planner with Phone Numbers, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Paulette Goddard Magazine Images, undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Planner with Expenses, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Life Magazine with Paulette Goddard on Cover, April 18, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Series VI: Telegrams from Eleonara Duse to Paul Lindau
    Series VI: Eleonara Duse telegrams contains a small number of telegrams from actress Eleonara Duse to theater director Paul Lindau. They have been retained in original order.
    - Telegrams from Eleonara Duse to Paul Lindau, 1918 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Series VII: Photographs
    Series VII: Photographs consists of photographs and glass plate negatives, and is separated into three subseries. Subseries A: Erich Remarque consists of photos that appear to date from the 1920s and 1930s and include images of cars, city scenes, and country roads with many pictures of an unidentified woman. Subseries B: Paulette Goddard consists primarily of film promotional stills, along with some personal shots. Subseries C: Art, furniture, jewelry, rugs consists of photos primarily of items belonging to the Remarques that appear to have been used in appraisals and sales.
    - Subseries A: Foldered Photographs
      - Photos, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Photos from "AGFA - Choromo - Isorapio - Platten" Box, undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Negatives and Photos from Perorto Box, undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Photo and Negatives from Hauff Ultra-Rapid Photo-Platten, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Negatives from "Papa's House! Good Fotos of E.M.R", undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Paulette Goddard - Photos, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Carpet Collection, undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Carpet Collection, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - Photos - Living Room of 320 E. 57th as of January 1986, Painting of Paulette Goddard by Diego Rivera, Paulette Goddard with [Charlie Chaplin] in Envelope Labeled "From Lois's Collection" (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Slides, Negatives from Small Leather Box - PG Swimming, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Photos from "Black Leather Album", 1957, 1958, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - 6 Photos of Alta Goddard, 1 of Paulette Goddard in Costume, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Carpet Photo and [Ruby] Necklace Photo, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Subseries B: Photo Binders
      - Paulette Goddard (Binder 45, Binder 46)
      - Art, furniture, jewelry (Binder 47)
    - Subseries C: Photo Albums
      - Paulette Goddard Photograph Album, undated (Box 53, Album 1)
      - Paulette Goddard Photograph Album: Traveling, undated (Box 53, Album 2)
        Includes wedding photos with Charlie Chaplin.
      - Paulette Goddard Photograph Album: Trip to W. Germany U.S. Military Bases, June 1-6, 1946 (Box 53, Album 3)
    - Subseries D: Glass Plate Negatives
      - Bicyclists, Cars, Pedestrians in Front of Brandenburg Gate (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Street View from Above (Berlin?), undated (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Car at Lake with People Getting Into Boat from Wicker Chair, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Cyclists Including One Uniformed and Cars in Street, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Two Women on Boat Named "Dehuma", undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Large Building with Sign - Gartenbau Ausstellung (Horticulture Exhibition), undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Two Women with Boat, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Car at Dock with Boats, undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Double Decker Grunewald Bus (Berlin?), undated (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Prenzlauer Allee Streetcar with Guard, People, Cars on Street, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - People Looking at Cars, undated (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Cars Lined Up in Street, undated (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Cars and People, undated (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Cars and Bikes, undated (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - Cars and Horses, undated (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - Cars and Carriages on Street, undated (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - Cars Behind Building, undated (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - Cars and Guard in Front of Large Building, undated (Box 50, Folder 18)
      - Street Car and Pedestrians on City Street (Berlin?), undated (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - Horse-drawn Carriage, Cars, Cyclists, Pedestrians on Street, undated (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - Street with Cars and People, undated (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - Cars on a Street, undated (Box 50, Folder 22)
      - City Street From Above (Berlin), undated (Box 50, Folder 23)
      - Cars and Cyclists on City Street (Berlin?), undated (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - Car on Road in Front of Trees, undated (Box 50, Folder 26)
      - Sailors and Others with Sailboat, undated (Box 50, Folder 27)
      - Car on Road with Woman, Trees Behind, undated (Box 50, Folder 28)
      - EMR and Woman Picnicking, Car and Trees in Background, undated (Box 50, Folder 29)
      - Woman in Car at Beach, undated (Box 50, Folder 30)
      - Erich Maria Remarque, undated (Box 50, Folder 31)
      - Woman in Car with Field and Tree, undated (Box 50, Folder 32)
      - Woman in Car with Woods in Background, undated (Box 50, Folder 33)
      - Woman in Hat with Car, undated (Box 50, Folder 34)
  - Series VIII: Film
    Series VIII: Film contains one film that is currently unavailable to researchers.
    - Watch Mr. Wizard, Undated; ID: 095.0001 (Reel 095.0001)
      An episode from the educational television program "Watch Mr. Wizard."
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Original Format: 16 mm TRT: Unknown
      Conditions Governing Access
      Currently unavailable.
  - Series IX: Audio and Video Recordings
    Series IX: Audio and Video recordings consists of at least one interview with Erich Remarque, along with a number of unidentified cassettes.
    - Subseries A: Audio
      - Remarque: 1, Undated; ID: 095.0003 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0003)
        Original Format: 1/4" Audiocassette
        TRT: Unknown
      - Remarque - 1, Undated; ID: 095.0004 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0004)
      - Remarque - 2, Undated; ID: 095.0005 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0005)
        Original Format: Audiocassette TRT: Unknown
      - Remarque 2-B, Undated; ID: 095.0006 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0006)
      - Remarque 3, Undated; ID: 095.0007 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0007)
      - Remarque 3 (The End), Undated; ID: 095.0008 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0008)
      - Remarque 4, Undated; ID: 095.0009 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0009)
      - Porto Ronco Verleihung der Moesermedaille des Stadt Osnabrueck an Erich Maria Remarque ca. 14 min, [1964 October]; ID: 095.0010 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0010)
        Original Format: Audiocassette TRT: [00:14:00]
    - Subseries B: Video
      - Das Profil Interview EMR mit Fr. Luft, [1963 January 28]; ID: 095.0002 (Box 51, Media ID: 095.0002)
        Original Format: VHS
        TRT: 00:31:02
  - Series X: Objects
    Series X: Objects consists of a handbag and portrait locket belonging to Paulette Goddard
    - Handbag with studs spelling "PAULETTE", undated (Box 52, Object ID: 095.2.0001)
    - Portrait resembling Paulette Goddard by Ruby Walker Usher on [brass] locket, undated (Box 52, Object ID: 095.2.0002)
  - OVERSIZE Series I: Literary properties
    - Subseries B: Arch of Triumph, circa 2000
      - Arch of Triumph Poster- Takarazuka musical stage adaptation, [2000] (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Arch of Triumph- Film Ad, [undated] (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Subseries D: Heaven has no favorites
      - "Zurcher Woche" [German language newspaper] - with excerpt from "Geborgtes Leben", March 11, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Subseries E: The Homecoming of Enoch J. Jones
      - "Die Heimkehr des Enoch J. Jones"- [poster], [undated] (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Subseries G: The Last Station
      - "Die Letzte Station" at Renaissance Theater Berlin- [photocopy of 1956 original], [undated] (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Subseries M: Spark of Life
      - Uncorrected Proofs- "Spark of Life", August 9, 1951 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Subseries N: Three Comrades
      - Three Comrades Poster [photocopy], [undated] (Box 49, Folder 7)
- Two VHS tapes (Box Shared Fales 106)